# Alex Mansfield

# **Full Stack Software Developer**

### **Contact**



Bristol, UK
mansfieldalex
alexjames4
portfolio



ajmansfield0@gmail.com

I am an empathetic, considerate and highly analytical individual with a drive for learning who is currently seeking an opportunity to begin a career as a Software Developer.

Having always had a passion for mathematics, problem-solving and technology I am searching for a career where I can continue to develop skills generated during my time on iO Academy's Full Stack Bootcamp whilst having a positive and meaningful impact to the world around me.

#### **Interests**

#### Game Jams

I have started to develop a game on the theme of 'SCALE' with a friend as part of the Itch.io 'Game Off 2023' using the Godot Engine

#### Cycling

I am a keen cyclist and love exploring the countryside on my bike scouting out the amazing views and pubs we have in the surrounding area.

### **Record Collecting**

Recently I have acquired a record player and have spent many joyful hours expanding my personal collection.

# Spending Time with my Dog

I have a 2 and a half year old Sprocker Spaniel called Cinder. She is a little chaos potato, who hates pigeons and loves leaves.

#### Music Festivals

I've been to many music festivals over the years including Glastonbury, Y Not and Womad.

# **Projects**

# **Academy Portal Application**

For this project, I had the chance to work with a legacy code base that has been worked on by all the previous cohorts of iO Academy. I utilised the Slim Framework to assist with the MVC architecture to add a feature to the courses page which allowed for visual differentiation between upcoming and future courses as well as a toggle button to show/hide completed courses. To do this I had to combine and utilise all of my HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP and MySQL skills I have acquired so far.

### Live Link GitHub

### Project Management API

For this project, as part of a team of 4 at iO Academy, I helped to design an Object-Oriented PHP API to work with a pre-built React front end so that projects were displayed detailing the people and tasks assigned to each with the correct success or error response message being displayed in line with a specified API documentation.

# Live Link GitHub

# **Email Client Application**

As part of a team at iO Academy, I helped to create an email client following a specified design which allowed the user to compose and display emails and signify whether they had been read/unread. This combined and improved my HTML, CSS and JavaScript proficiency through usage of the React and Bootstrap Frameworks. Live Link GitHub

# **Certifications**

Agile Professional Jul Certification 2023

iO Academy

Full UK Driving Feb License 2009

# Skills

HTML CSS

JavaScript TypeScript

PHP MySQL

C# React

Slim MongoDB

Node.js Git

# **Employment History**

**Limber** Oct 2023 – present

Part-time kitchen work

Electric Bear Brewing Co. Jan 2018 – Mar 2022

Assistant Head Brewer

Whilst working at EB I demonstrated my ability to work effectively in a team to a tight schedule, ensuring that multiple tasks were completed correctly and simultaneously by the production team ensuring that the final product was of the high standard that stakeholders expected.

**The Malago** Oct 2015 – Dec 2017

Sous Chef

During my time at the Malago I demonstrated my ability to multitask under high levels of pressure and my capacity to learn and implement new skills.

**Arbor Ales** Sep 2014 – Sep 2015

Brewer

**RPS Group** Aug 2013 – Aug 2014

Graduate Safety Case Consultant

# Education

**Full Stack Software Developer** Jul 2023 – Oct 2023

Bootcamp

iO Academy, Bath

A 16-week bootcamp where I have learnt a range of different front-end and back-end programming languages through taught theory and subsequent application of the theory through a range of individual and team-based projects.

Secondary PGCE with Physics Sep 2022 – May

Specialism 2023

Bath Spa University

MEng Chemical EngineeringSep 2009 – Jul 2013University of Birmingham2:1 (with Hons)

**A Levels & GCSEs** Sep 2002 – Jul 2009

The Blue School, Wells

A Levels: AAA Mathematics, Physics and Chemistry AS Levels: A - Further Mathematics, B - Biology

GCSEs: 10 GCSEs

A\* - English Literature, Music, Maths A – History, Chemistry, Physics,

Biology, English Language, Citizenship B – Economics